# Ben Griffin

Portland, OR • +1 253-720-8238 • bengriffin.me@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/bencgriffin

# **Staff Software Engineer**

10+ years of software engineering experience with an emphasis on design systems and modern JS frameworks. 7+ years working on e-commerce applications. Led the development of REI Co-op's design system and modernized REI's frontend platform in 6 months by leading the migration to Vue 3. Pragmatic problem-solver with a track record for crafting accessible and seamless user experiences.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Sony, Sony Network Communications Of America

03/2024 - 04/2024

This business was shut down shortly after I joined due to changing strategy at Sony.

#### **Technical Lead**

- Hired to lead the planning, execution, and delivery of front end software for a new, high-growth startup bringing a premium fiber-to-the-home internet service to the US.
- Architected a robust, multi-platform design system using Storybook and Style Dictionary to output a custom Tailwind configuration, increasing engineering efficiency by 50%.
- Created Quality Management Strategy (QMS) in my first two weeks to ensure web application performance and accessibility; presented to Sony leadership.

# REI Co-op 07/2017 - 03/2024

# Senior Software Engineer, Design Systems

- Led the development, maintenance and release management of REI's open-source design system, Cedar, encompassing UI components, design tokens, patterns, documentation, and guidelines
- Distributed efficient and reusable component library that greatly improved presentation, reliability, maintainability and accessibility for REI.com, resulting in dramatic reductions in time-to-market and millions of dollars in developer resource savings
- Improved application resilience and developer productivity by spearheading the introduction of TypeScript to the REI Engineering community
- Led a quarterly cross-discipline collaboration with engineers, designers and product managers to refine and prioritize requests and translate them into high-quality deliverables
- Engineered a design system documentation platform using Nuxt, Vue and AWS. Automated component documentation, streamlining processes and improving team efficiency.
- Championed accessibility by automating e2e WCAG 2.2 AA accessibility testing for the component library, reducing production errors by 50%

- Mentored engineers on best practices, streamlined code reviews by facilitating real-time collaboration, reducing comments by 45%
- Created onboarding training for UX designers and PMs that walked through how REI.com works at a level understandable to a non-technical audience, resulting in increased team productivity and performance

### Software Engineer, Digital Publishing Systems

- Crafted search-optimized digital experiences for enterprise e-commerce micro applications, increasing organic demand and ranking by 25%
- Lowered technical overhead 80% and increased Time-to-Market 50% by migrating all landing pages from a monolith to a new micro-frontend platform within one year
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design RESTful API's for consumption from headless
  CMS platforms, improving UX by 30% and streamlining content delivery

### **Technical Producer**

- Operationalized landing page experiences by developing a reusable library of compositional components, driving \$30,000,000+ in sales/day
- Closely partnered with marketing and brand teams to develop highly visible and highly engaging interactive experiences, such as the viral "Opt Outside" campaign, while ensuring a performant and accessible experience for all

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor Of Arts Integrated Media**

Pacific University • Forest Grove, OR, USA

08/2007 - 05/2011

Integrated Media is a hybrid major consisting of frontend engineering, UI/UX design, and project management. I also completed many courses towards a Computer Science minor (OOP, DSA), but did not complete the degree prior to graduation.

### **SKILLS**

**Languages & Frameworks:** CSS, HTML, Java, JavaScript, LESS, Next.js, Node.js, Nuxt.js, React.js, SASS, TypeScript, Vue.js

**Techniques:** A/B Testing, Accessibility, Agile Software Development, CI/CD, Responsive Design, SEO, Server Side Rendering, System Design, Unit testing, UX, Web Performance

**Tools:** AWS, Bitbucket, Continuous Integration, Figma, GraphQL, Jest, MySQL, REST APIs, Rollup, Shopify, Storybook, Style Dictionary, Vite, Vitest, Webpack, Webpack